<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://www.gobosoft.com/eiffel/gobo/documentation" id="city3d/user/mouse_controls">
<chapterinfo>
	<copyright>
		<year>2005</year>
		<holder>Michela Pedroni</holder>
	</copyright>
    <email>michela.pedroni@inf.ethz.ch</email>
	<date>$Date$</date>
</chapterinfo>

<title>Mouse and keyboard controls</title>
<section id="Mouse controls">
	<title>Mouse controls</title>
	<para>
	 i) Mouse wheel:
	Controls the zooming factor, whereas the position stays invariant. 
	There are two different zooming speeds depending on the distance to the plane.
	</para>
	<para>
	 ii) Mouse click:
	Is used to mark stations on the map. The origin can be marked with the 
	left mouse button, the destination with the right one. If the user clicks 
	on an empty spot, the marked stations are revoked.
	</para>
	<para>
	 iii) Mouse dragging:
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>
                Left mouse button: By dragging the mouse while pressing the left 
                button one is able to translate the position of the map in the 
                window, i.e. move the plane.
            </para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>
                Right mouse button: By dragging the mouse while pressing the right 
                button one is able to rotate the map around the the origin.
            </para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
	</para>
	<para>
	 iv) Keyboard:
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>
                By pressing the up-/down- or left-/right- arrow keys the map will be rotated around the x- or y-axis respectively.
            </para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>
                By pressing the enter key the translation will be reset to its initial value. However, zoom as well as rotation aren't affected.
            </para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
	</para>
	<title>Options</title>
    <para>
        <image src="image/right_options.png"/>
    </para>
	
	<para>
		<para>
			i) Choose the map to be loaded and load it.
		</para>
		<para>
			ii) Zoom in and out.
		</para>
		<para>
	 		iii) Change the number of buildings to be randomly displayed on the map: The number of buildings can be varied from 0 up to 4900. 
	 	</para>
	 	<para>
			iv) Make the buildings transparent in order to achieve a better overview.
		</para>
		<para>
			v) Change lighting of the map: Initially, the scene is lit by a constant light coming down the y axis. 
			However, this can be changed to a variable light that tries to imitate the effect of the sun.
		</para>
		<para>
			vi) Show a coordinate system: This shows a coordinate system at the origin for better orientation.
		</para>
		<para>
			vii) Highlight the traffic lines by drawing them with different height on the map, in order to achieve a better overview.
		</para>
		<para>
			viii) The buildings can be hidden or shown by enabling/disabling the "show buildings" option.
		</para>
		<para>	
			ix) Show the shortest path between two marked stations and display it as a white line. The origin for the route 
			is marked by clicking on the place with the left mouse button and the destination with the right mouse button.
		</para>
		<para>
			x) When two stations are selected, a new button appears. If you press it, you can take a traffic 
			line ride in a first-person perspective between the two marked stations.
	 	</para>
	</para>
	<para>
        <image src="image/right_options.png"/>
    </para>
    <para>
		<para>
		i) Shows the name of the most recently marked building.
		</para>
		<para>
		ii) Choose the XML file for building loading and load them.
		</para>
		<para>
		iii) Load buildings along all traffic lines (expect railway).
		</para>
		<para>
		iv) Delete all buildings.
		</para>
    </para>
<toplink/>
</section>
</chapter>
