<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!--
	description:

		"Introduction to the Traffic 3D front end documentation"

	copyright: ""
	license: ""
	date: ""
	revision: ""
-->

<chapter xmlns="http://www.gobosoft.com/eiffel/gobo/documentation" id="sample/with_code">
<chapterinfo>
	<copyright>
		<year>2005</year>
		<holder>David Stefan, Valentin Wüstholz</holder>
	</copyright>
	<author>
		<firstname>David</firstname><surname>Stefan</surname>
	</author>
    <author>
		<firstname>Valentin</firstname><surname>Wüstholz</surname>
	</author>
	<!--<email>bay@inf.ethz.ch</email>-->
	<date>12. September 2005</date>
</chapterinfo>

<title>Introduction</title>
<section id="page_index">
<title>Page Index</title>
<para>
<itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
    <para>
    	<indexlink url="#purpose">Purpose of this work</indexlink>
    </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
    <para>
    	<indexlink url="#goals">Goals</indexlink>
    </para>
    </listitem>
     <listitem>
    <para>
    	<indexlink url="#environment">Environment and used libraries</indexlink>
    </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
    <para>
    	<indexlink url="#structure">Structure of the documentation</indexlink>
    </para>
    </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para>
</section>
<section id="purpose">
	<para/>
	<title>Purpose of this work</title>
	<para>
	The purpose of this work was to provide a 3
	dimensional visualization of a map from an XML file. 
	This map contains information about places and traffic
	lines of a city which should be displayed in an appropriate way. 
	</para>
<toplink/>
</section>

<section id="goals">
	<para/>
	<title>Our goals</title>
	<para>
	Our goal was to implement a program that parses this
	map file, generates the data structures, displays traffic lines as
	colored polygons on a plane, adds buildings on this plane
	randomly but checks for 'collisions' with traffic lines and provides useful mouse and keyboard support such that changing
	the viewpoint (zooming, rotation, different centres) should be
	possible (easily). Moreover different light settings should be
	implemented and existing features such as the shortest path
	algorithm integrateted and visualized.
	</para>
<toplink/>
</section>
<section id="environment">
	<para/>
	<title>Environment and used libraries</title>
	<para>
    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para>
    	EiffelStudio 5.5
    </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>
    	GOBO
    </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>
    	EWG
    </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>
    	EiffelMedia Library: Provides the Components for
	doing the whole graphics such as the access to the SDL
	commands or the widgets that were used for the GUI.
    </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>
    	TRAFFIC  Library: Provides the whole map parsing,
	data structures and things like the calculation of the
	shortest path.
    </para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
	</para>
<toplink/>
</section>

<section id="structure">
	<para/>
	<title>Structure of the documentation</title>
	<para>
    <para>
	<ulink url="structure.html">The next part</ulink> explaines the overall structure and all the used classes and factories with their most important features. 
    </para>
    <para>
	<ulink url="miscellaneous.html">Part three</ulink> explaines which
	parts are depending on the information in the XML files and
	which features would have to be changed using different ones. Moreover it discusses some possible reuse scenarios of our work. It explains how control options
	are added to the GUI and what would have to be done if one would like to change more than just the GUI. Finally, it presents some ideas of what could be implemented in
	the future and how to embed it into the project.
    </para>
	</para>
<toplink/>
</section>

</chapter>
