<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!--
	description:

		"Traffic 3D front end documentation"

	copyright: "Copyright (c) 2005, Till Bay and others"
	license: "Eiffel Forum License v2 (see forum.txt)"
	date: "$Date$"
	revision: "$Revision$"
-->

<chapter xmlns="http://www.gobosoft.com/eiffel/gobo/documentation" id="sample/with_code">
<chapterinfo>
	<copyright>
		<year>2005</year>
		<holder>David Stefan, Valentin Wüstholz</holder>
	</copyright>
	<author>
		<firstname>David</firstname><surname>Stefan</surname>
	</author>
    <author>
		<firstname>Valentin</firstname><surname>Wüstholz</surname>
	</author>
	<!--<email>bay@inf.ethz.ch</email>-->
	<date>12. September 2005</date>
</chapterinfo>

<title>Miscellaneous</title>
<section id="page_index">
<title>Page Index</title>
<para>
<itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para>
    	<indexlink url="#dependencies">Dependencies</indexlink>
    </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>
    	<indexlink url="#reuseability">Reuseability</indexlink>
    </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>
    	<indexlink url="#future_perspective">Future perspective</indexlink>
    </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para>
</section>
<section id="installation">
	<title>Dependencies</title>
    <para>
        This section lists some things that are kind of ugly in the sense that they may not work perfectly if some parameters are changed.
    </para>
    <para>
    1) Map files:
        they must be in the map subdirectory and in the main directory. This is some deficiency of the TRAFFIC Library and will probably be fixed someday.
    </para>
    <para>
    2) in <classname>SHARED_CONSTANTS</classname>:
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>
                <featurename>Plane_size</featurename> is magic number that is chosen with our example maps in mind. This works for them but it might not work perfectly for other map files. So this might have to be changed or made independent of the map file by either calculating it somehow or saving it in some configuration file.
            </para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>
                <featurename>map_to_gl_coords</featurename> is also optimized for our example maps. They use the range of the coordinates from the map.
            </para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>

<toplink/>
</section>

<section id="reuseability">
	<title>Reuseability</title>
	<para>
		This section discusses some scenarios of how you could reuse our work.
	</para>
    <para>
		 1) change some minor things like the representation of the traffic lines or the buildings:
         <para>
            You could directly change the related classes. e.g. <classname>TRAFFIC_LINE_FACTORY</classname> or<classname>BUILDING_FACTORY</classname>. This should have immediate consequences on their graphical representation.
         </para>
	</para>
	<para>
		 2) keep everything and add some new features like the ones we put on the toolbar:
         <para>
            You would have to add the new features in <classname>MAP</classname> and make them accessible by adding corresponding controle options to the GUI by changing <classname>CITY_3D_SCENE</classname>.
         </para>
	</para>
    <para>
		 3) keep the MAP class and replace the GUI:
         <para>
            You could also throw away our GUI and replace it with your own or just integrate the 'map part' of the application into your own application. This could easily be done by just creating an instance of <classname>MAP</classname> in your application. Then you could use the features you like or even add new features to <classname>MAP</classname>.
         </para>
	</para>
<toplink/>
</section>

<section id="future_perspective">
	<title>Future perspective</title>
	<para>
		This section lists some things one could do in the future to inprove or enhance what we have do so far.
	</para>
	<para>
    1) new features:
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>
                First-person traveling through the city
            </para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>
                extra XML file with things especially for the 3D map
            </para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para>
    2) extensions:
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>
                Text console or other GUI extensions
            </para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>
                time tables for the means of transport; maybe updateable over the internet
            </para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>
                Integration of Events like concerts, cinemas, theaters etc.
            </para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para>
    3) improvements:
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>
                faster parsing of the XML file
            </para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>
                even more speed optimizations for the Graphics
            </para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>
                more buildings etc. - would probably need an extra XML file
            </para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para>
    4) completely new things:
        
    </para>
<toplink/>
</section>

</chapter>
