<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
	description:

		"User guide for Touch"

	copyright: "Copyright (c) 2005, Roger Kueng"
	license: "Eiffel Forum License v2 (see forum.txt)"
-->
<chapter xmlns="http://www.gobosoft.com/eiffel/gobo/documentation" id="user_guide">
    <chapterinfo>
        <copyright>
            <year>2005</year>
            <holder>Roger Kueng</holder>
        </copyright>
        <author>
            <firstname>Roger</firstname>
            <surname>Kueng</surname>
        </author>
        <email>rkueng@student.ethz.ch</email>
        <date>29 September 2005</date>
    </chapterinfo>
    <title>Touch Userguide</title>
    <para>
    	TOUCH is the second application that is delivered to you. 
			TOUCH implements some of the examples of the book ''Touch of Class''. 
			Note that the examples as described in TOUCH are not totally equivalent 
			to their description in the text book. At the time of this writing not 
			all the examples of the book are implemented yet. So TOUCH needs to be 
			taken with a pinch of salt!
    </para>

    <para>
        <image src="image/touch_preview_window.jpg"/>
    </para>
    <para>
        <emphasis>Figure 1: The Main Window</emphasis>
    </para>
    
		<section id="application">
			<title>
				How does this application work?
			</title>
			<para>
				Each chapter respectively each example has its own application. All look almost the same 
				for except some minor changes to meet the requirements of the individual exercise. 
				The window has on its right side the control panel where the user can zoom in or zoom out.
				Dependant on the exercise there are more buttons to click (for example a restart button etc.).

			<--	On the left side you can see the chapters and their examples. To change 
				between the examples from the book and the exercises use the two buttons 
				on the bottom left of the screen. Simply click on an example and some 
				information together with a picture will pop up on the right side. To see the example 
				in action use the <emphasis>run example</emphasis> button on the right. What
				happens after you pressed the button depends on the implementation of the 
				example, but in most of the examples you will get a screen like this    
			-->
			</para>
	    <para>
	        <image src="image/map_sm.png"/>
	    </para>
	    <para>
	        <emphasis>Figure 2: Example Scene </emphasis>
	    </para>
	    <para>
				 You navigate on the map by pressing the mouse buttons. 
			</para>
      <para>
      	  <itemizedlist>
	        <listitem>
	            <para> Pressing the right mouse button while moving the mouse will scroll the map. 
	            </para>
	        </listitem>
	        <listitem>
	            <para>Moving the mouse up or down while pressing the middle mouse button will zoom in or out. 
	            </para>
	        </listitem>
	        <listitem>
	            <para>Clicking the left mouse button will select places or lines.
	            </para>
	        </listitem>
      	  </itemizedlist>
	    </para>				 
		<para>	 
 				To get back to the menu simply click the <emphasis>End Example</emphasis> button.    
	    </para>
		</section>    
</chapter>