<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://www.gobosoft.com/eiffel/gobo/documentation" id="guide/changes">
<chapterinfo>
	<copyright>
		<year>2006</year>
		<holder>Matthias Loeu</holder>
	</copyright>
    <email>mloeu@inf.ethz.ch</email>
	<date>$Date: 2006-12-14 13:22:06 +0200 (Thu, 14 Dec 2006) $</date>
</chapterinfo>
    <title>Getting Started Guide</title>
	
    <section id="installation_audience">
        <title>Changes to Traffic</title>
        <para>There are some bugs in the release version (3.1) of Traffic.</para>
		<para>Most of the bugs don't affect the user directly. Two however I have to point out since your application might not work:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>This bug is fixed in the developement version of Traffic and thus presumably also in any future release. If you create a Touch application and save it somewhere outside the "/traffic/example" folder your application crashes because an icon is missing/not where it thinks it is. There are various solutions/workarounds to this problem: (you need only apply ONE of the points listed below!)</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>In TOUCH_3D_APPLICATION: remove line 43 (set_window_icon...)</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Make a copy of the icon at the location stated on line 43 in the class TOUCH_3D_APPLICATION, relative to where your application is.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Again, if you create a Touch application outside the example folder of the Traffic application your application crashes because it searches for some images which are not at the expected place any more. I don't know of a good solution, a workaround is to either copy the "buildings" folder to where your application is or to change lines 54, 61, 120 and 128 of the class TRAFFIC_3D_BUILDING_FANCY_FACTORY to reflect the path changes. For example, if the Traffic library is on "D:\traffic", you have to replace the two dots ".." with "D:\traffic\example" on all of the lines stated above.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>There are a few other similiar bugs. If you are unsure why your application crashes, try placing it in the "example" folder in the Traffic library.</para>
    </section>
</chapter>
