<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://www.gobosoft.com/eiffel/gobo/documentation" id="guide/example">
<chapterinfo>
	<copyright>
		<year>2006</year>
		<holder>Matthias Loeu</holder>
	</copyright>
    <email>mloeu@inf.ethz.ch</email>
	<date>$Date: 2006-12-14 13:22:06 +0200 (Thu, 14 Dec 2006) $</date>
</chapterinfo>
    <title>Getting Started Guide</title>
	
    <section id="example">
        <title>Run example applications</title>
        <para>Traffic comes with some included applications such as Flat Hunt. They are located in the respective directory under traffic/example.</para>
		<para>Some of the directories do not contain an application but common files that are used by the applications. These are buildings, image, map and objects.</para>
		<para>These applications show some of the capabilities of traffic. They all need to be compiled first to run. </para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Start EiffelStudio.</para>
				<para><image src="p/p6.png"/></para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>In the start dialog choose "Add Project". If the dialog does not appear, click on "File ->New Project...".</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>This will open a file dialog that lets you choose the *.ecf file of the application you whish to compile. Browse to the directory where the application is located (e.g. D:\traffic\example\flat_hunt), choose the *.ecf file (flat_hunt.ecf) and click on “Open”.</para>
				<para><image src="p/p7.png"/></para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Back in the start dialog, select your project click on "Open". </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Alternatively, open the folder containing the application you want to start and dobule-click the *.ecf file. This will start EiffelStudio with the wizard.</para>
				<para><image src="p/p8.png"/></para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>This will start the compilation of the application. Before doing so you may need to change the Location, however this shouldn't be the case.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Go get a coffee. Depending on your computer you may wait a while or an even longer while...</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Once the project is compiled you can execute (debug) it by clicking on the  "Debug" button in EiffelStudio or by hitting F5.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<para></para>
		<para></para>
		<para></para>
		<para></para>
    </section>
</chapter>
