<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://www.gobosoft.com/eiffel/gobo/documentation" id="guide/new/traffic">
<chapterinfo>
	<copyright>
		<year>2006</year>
		<holder>Matthias Loeu</holder>
	</copyright>
    <email>mloeu@inf.ethz.ch</email>
	<date>$Date: 2006-12-14 13:22:06 +0200 (Thu, 14 Dec 2006) $</date>
</chapterinfo>
    <title>Getting Started Guide</title>
	
    <section id="new_traffic">
        <title>The Traffic library</title>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Start EiffelStudio</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>In the start dialog, in the section “Create project” choose “Basic application (no graphics library included)” and click “Create”.</para>
				<image src="p/p10.png"/>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>On the next screen, you can choose the name of your application as well as the directory in which all the files are located, if you're done, click “OK”.</para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>I recommend to set the “System name”, “Root cluster” and “Root class” the same, to the name of your application. Unless of course you want to create a Touch Application (see below). The “Root feature” should remain “make”.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Choose the location of your application. I recommend not to set it somewhere inside the Traffic folder as that may lead to some confusion. </para>
						<image src="p/p20.png"/>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>If you have checked “Compile project”, EiffelStudio will compile your application, if not click on the “Compile” button or F7 on your keyboard.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Open your project settings (the button left of “Compile”).</para>
				<image src="p/p21.png"/>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Click on the “Add library” button (or press Ctrl-L), select “gobo” and click “OK”. This will include the gobo library (part of EiffelMedia) to your application.</para>
				<image src="p/p22.png"/>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Now include EiffelMedia itself: Click on “Add library”, then on “Browse”. Browse to the location where you have installed EiffelMedia, in the subfolder “library” there is “em.ecf”. Select that file and click “OK”, and again “OK”.</para>
				<image src="p/p12.png"/>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Repeat the above step with Traffic. In the “library” subfolder select “traffic.ecf”.</para>
				<image src="p/p11.png"/>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Again, compile your application. This will take a while, so go make yourself a cup of tea.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
        <para>Now your application is ready to use the Traffic library. If you run your application you may notice that nothing happens. This is because you didn't actually tell your program what to do, only what it is and where it can find the stuff it needs.</para>
    </section>
</chapter>
